SABRIN OTHMAN

CONTACT

1389 Giel Ave, Lakewood, Ohio 44107

9174467394

SKILLS

- Bilingual speaker in Arabic and English.
- Influenced and negotiated with decisionmakers to achieve business objectives.
- Developed stakeholder communications and training to support process implementation.
- Reconciled account status using current and historical invoicing and payment activity analysis.
- Educated customers on features and benefits of products and provided demonstrations.
- Addressed customer inquiries and concerns using extensive product knowledge.
- Handled the integration of benefits systems for employees in newly acquired subsidiaries.

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self-motivated, passionate and driven Account Specialist. Meet with clients and discuss projects with clients based on specific requests and market research. Formulate customized marketing strategies and define advertising budgets. Present business pitches to clients and organize focus groups.

EXPERIENCE

MetLife Legal Plans | Cleveland, OH

October 2022 - Current

Account Specialist

- Organized information by maintaining databases, calendars and filing systems.
- Utilized advanced knowledge of product and legal plan services to recommend products and troubleshoot service issues.
- Engaged with customers to better understand needs and requirements and find appropriate solutions.
- Maintained communication records, utilized different applications to maintain data like salesforce, excel, ibmi, renewal tracker.
- Attended and set up stewardship and other types of meetings to discuss utilization reports and legal plan renewal strategies.
- Worked with major brokerage companies and legal plan sponsors.
- Prepared and presented utilization reports, schedule A, and other financial and business reports to plan sponsors and other key stake holders

MetLife Legal Plans | Cleveland, Ohio

January 2022 - October 2022

Panel Relations Specialist

- Built and maintained great relationships with legal plan contracted attorneys.
- Resolved escalated issues with dissatisfied legal plan members and attorneys.
- Made informed decisions under stressful circumstances.
- Solved issues and inquires about legal plan coverage from attorneys and plan members.
- Assisted attorneys with billing inquires and issues.
- Provided key information to supervisors regarding customer issues or complaints.
- Maintained a records with relevant information in Zendesk, Ibmi, excel, and other applications.
- Updated clients with status updates on their pending legal cases, while maintaining confidential information.

${\bf MetLife\ Legal\ Plans\ |\ Cleveland\ ,\ ohio}$

October 2021 - January 2022

Client Service Representative

- Multitasked to resolve inquiries in real time, whilst giving customers full attention.
- Entered and updated customer data to create and modify account information.
- Assisted plan members with creating and trouble shooting issues on the legal plan website.
- Listened actively to complaints, feedback and feature requests for future improvement.
- Obtained necessary personal information and verified eligibility in real time.
- Created and resolved eligibility, legal plan coverage, and escalated inquiries.

Gibson, Moran and Gibson | Akron, Ohio

• August 2021 - October 2021

Bankruptcy Paralegal

- Scheduled client meetings and prepared meeting documents and minutes.
- Acted as critical go-to partner for business stakeholders in company and legal department.
- Researched related statutes, decisions, and codes to support each case.

- Organized supporting materials and prepared exhibits for trial cases.
- Managed logistics for delivery of documents for court proceedings and meetings.

Yemeni American Merchant Association | brooklyn, ny

• August 2019 - August 2021

Director of Advocacy

- Continuously evaluated community's needs to adapt program's offerings accordingly.
- Collaborated with senior staff members to provide united leadership to employees.
- Spearheaded fundraising activities to raise capital to invest in services.
- Implemented skills development programs for staff and volunteers, keeping staff up to date on training needs.
- Assisted with research and resolution of legal complaints.
- Processed filing of court documents and collated evidence and other legal documents for case files.
- Conducted and set up community training sessions on Facebook live and in person for know your rights, merchant and immigrant rights.
- Conducted presentations in english and arabic

EDUCATION

May 2019

Bachelor of Science - Economics
John Jay College of Criminal Justice, New York City, NY

LANGUAGES

Arabic

Native